
孩子们  吃早饭了                             Kids, breakfast!                                      														
孩子们  |                                   |Kids? 
菲尔  把他们叫下来好吗|                                   |Phil, would you get them?
好  等一下|                                   |Yeah. Just a sec.
孩子们|                                   |Kids!
-这真是  -算了|                                   |- That is - Okay.
孩子们  快下来|                                   |Kids? Get down here!
我们远在楼上  你们喊也没用|                                   |Why are you guys yelling at us when we're way upstairs?
-发个短信不就行了  -那是不可能的|                                   |- Just text me. - All right. That's not gonna happen.
你不能穿这套衣服出门|                                   |And, wow! You're not wearing that outfit.
这衣服怎么了|                                   |What's wrong with it?
亲爱的  对你女儿这条裙子|                                   |Honey, do you have anything to say
-有什么意见吗  -不好意思|                                   |- to your daughter about her skirt? - Sorry.
-挺可爱的嘛  宝贝  -谢了|                                   |- Oh, yeah. That looks really cute, sweetheart. - Thanks.
不行  这裙子太短了|                                   |No. It's way too short.
大家知道你是女生|                                   |People know you're a girl.
没必要穿这么少给他们看|                                   |You don't need to prove it to them.
卢克又把头卡在栏杆里了|                                   |Luke got his head stuck in the banister again.
我去吧  婴儿油在哪儿|                                   |I got it. Where's the baby oil?
在我们床头的  我不知道  你自己找|                                   |It's on our bedside tab- I don't know. Find it.
拜托|                                   |Come on!
菲尔&克莱尔
我在成长期间简直无法无天|                                   |I was out of control growing up.
你看  我坦白了|                                   |There, you know? I said it.
结婚16年
我只是不想让我的孩子|                                   |I-I just don't want my kids...
重蹈我的覆辙|                                   |to make the same bad mistakes I made.
只要海莉没有半裸着在佛罗里达沙滩上醒来|                                   |I-If Haley never wakes up on a beach in Florida, half-naked,
我就算完成我的任务了|                                   |I've done my job.
-我俩的任务  -对|                                   |- Our job. - Right.
我就算完成了我俩的任务|                                   |I've done our job.
加油  曼尼  踢球啊  踢啊|                                   |Vamos, Manny! Kick it! Kick it!
别让他  踢啊|                                   |Don't let him- Kick it!
曼尼  加油  往右跑  往右|                                   |Manny, go! A la derecha! A la derecha!
不  不  不要啊|                                   |No! No, no.
他下绊子  杰  怎么没人吹犯规|                                   |He tripped him, Jay. Where's the penalty?
歌洛莉亚  他们已经落后了6个球|                                   |Gloria, they're 0 and 6.
你小点声叫喊|                                   |Let's take it down a notch.
杰&歌洛莉亚
结婚6个月
我们是不同世界的人|                                   |We're very different.
杰来自城市|                                   |Jay's from the city.
他的生意做得很大|                                   |He has a big business.
我来自一个小山村|                                   |I come from a small village.
穷困潦倒  但风景怡人|                                   |Very poor but very, very beautiful.
我们村拥有全哥伦比亚最多的|                                   |It's the number one village in all Colombia for all the-
那个词怎么说来着|                                   |What's the word?
凶杀案|                                   |Murders.
没错  凶杀案|                                   |Yes. The murders.
曼尼  拦住他|                                   |Manny, stop him!
拦住他  你可以的|                                   |Stop him! You can do it!
你真烂  曼尼|                                   |Damn it, Manny!
教练  该让那孩子下场了|                                   |Come on, coach. You gotta take that kid out.
你想让他下场吗  不如我让你"下场"如何|                                   |You wanna take him out? How about I take you out?
-亲爱的  -你还是操心你的儿子吧|                                   |- Honey, honey. - Why don't you worry about your son?
他整个上半场光忙着抓裤裆了|                                   |He spent the first half with his hand in his pants!
那话我6周来一直想对她说来着|                                   |I've wanted to tell her off for the last six weeks.
我叫乔希  莱恩的爸爸|                                   |I'm Josh. Ryan's dad.
我叫歌洛莉亚·普里契特  曼尼的妈妈|                                   |Hi, I'm Gloria Pritchett. Manny's mother.
-这位是你父亲吧  -她父亲?|                                   |- Oh, and this must be your dad. - Her dad?
-是啊  -不  不是  真搞笑|                                   |- Yeah. - No, no. That's funny.
怎么可能  我是她老公|                                   |Actually, no, I'm her husband.
别被外表给骗了|                                   |Don't be fooled by the, uh-
稍等片刻|                                   |Give me a second here.
谁是乖宝宝啊  是谁啊  |                                   |Who is a good girl? Who's that?
是谁啊|                                   |Who's that?
-她真可爱  -谢谢|                                   |- Oh, she's adorable. - Oh, thank you.
你好  小公主|                                   |Hi, precious. Hello.
我们刚从越南领养了她|                                   |Uh, we just, uh- We just adopted her from Vietnam.
这是我们第一次带她回家|                                   |And we're bringing her home for the first time, huh?
她像个小天使  你们夫妻俩一定很激动|                                   |She's an angel. You and your wife must be thrilled.
抱歉  我来晚了  老爹去买点心了|                                   |Sorry, sorry, sorry. Daddy needed snacks.
大家在聊什么呢|                                   |So, what are we talking about?
我们在一起已经...5年了吧?|                                   |Uh, we have been together for- guh, five- five years now?
我们非常想要一个孩子|                                   |And, uh, we just- we decided we really wanted to have a baby.
           米奇尔&卡梅隆
一开始  我们想找一个|                                   |So, we had initially asked one of our
女同性恋朋友做代孕母亲|                                   |lesbian friends to be a surrogate, but-
后来又想  她们平时就够刻薄了|                                   |Then we figured, they're already mean enough.
你能想象她们怀孕后会如何变本加厉吗|                                   |Can you imagine one of 'em pregnant? Pregnant, no.
还是算了吧  想想就怕|                                   |No, thank you. Ick.
你看到没  大家本来在逗莉莉玩|                                   |You saw that, right? Everybody fawning over Lily,
你一走进来  他们就装作|                                   |and then you walk on and suddenly it's all,
看机上购物杂志|                                   |"Ooh, SkyMall.
考虑买个电动领带架什么的|                                   |I gotta buy a motorized tie rack."
我得教育一下这帮人|                                   |All right, you know, I'm gonna give the speech.
千万别这么做|                                   |You are not giving the speech.
你还得和他们一起呆上5小时呢|                                   |You're gonna be stuck with these people for the next five hours.
好吧  你说得对  我错了|                                   |You're right, you're right. Okay. I'm sorry.
[Cream Puffs  意为泡芙或者娘娘腔]
-你看那个拿着泡芙的宝宝  -好吧  够了|                                   |- Look at that baby with those cream puffs. - Okay. Excuse me.
不好意思|                                   |Excuse me.
这宝宝原本可能会在人满为患的孤儿院里成长|                                   |This baby would have grown up in a crowded orphanage
多亏我们这些娘娘腔收养呢|                                   |if it wasn't for us "Cream puffs."
-你们这些搞歧视的人  -米奇尔|                                   |- And you know what? Note to all of you who judge- - Mitchell!
给我听好了  爱不分种族  信仰|                                   |Hear this. Love knows no race, creed-
不分性别|                                   |Or gender.
-我为你们感到羞耻  -米奇尔|                                   |- And shame on you, - Mitchell.
-你们这些狭隘愚昧的  -米奇尔|                                   |- you small-minded, ignorant few - Mitchell!
-干嘛  -人家说的是泡芙|                                   |- What? -She's got the cream puffs.
各位的耳机费我们请了|                                   |We would like to pay for everyone's headsets.

摩登家庭\N第一季第一集
兄弟  你怎么老是卡在这里面|                                   |Buddy. Why do you keep getting stuck like this?
我以为这次能拔出来呢|                                   |I thought I could get out this time.
我直说了吧  他得去检查一下智商|                                   |I'm just gonna say it. He needs to be checked by a specialist.
好了  你自由了|                                   |There. Be free.
亚瑟王之剑拔出来了|                                   |Excalibur.
-今天我有朋友来家里玩  -谁啊 |                                   |- I'm having a friend over today. - Who?
-你不认识他  -是个男生吗|                                   |- Uh, you don't know him. - Him? Him?
哇  男生  你会和他亲嘴吗|                                   |Ooh, a boy. You gonna kiss him?
-闭嘴  -别激动  别激动|                                   |- Shut up. - Easy. Easy.
-闭嘴  -你才闭嘴|                                   |- Yeah, shut up! - No, you shut up!
卢克和艾丽克斯  你们俩出去解决好吗|                                   |Luke, Alex, why don't you take it outside, okay?
怎么解决|                                   |And do what?
-在太阳下决斗  不错吧  -海莉|                                   |- Fight in the sun. It'll be a nice change. - Haley.
-我逗你们玩呢  -是谁要来|                                   |- I'm kidding. - Who's the boy?
他叫迪兰|                                   |His name is Dylan.
我还是别让他来算了|                                   |I might as well tell him not to come...
不然你们又得让我丢脸|                                   |Because you guys are just going to embarrass me again.
亲爱的  等等|                                   |Sweetie, hang on a second.
你15岁了  还是第一次有男生来家里|                                   |You're 15, and it's the first time you've had a boy over.
我是有点小吃惊|                                   |I'm bound to be a little surprised,
可我不会让你丢脸的|                                   |but I'm not gonna embarrass you.
我去给摄像机充好电|                                   |I better charge the camcorder.
逗你玩呢  别这样  也不看看我是谁|                                   |I'm kidding. Come on. Who are you talking to?
我是酷老爹  这是我的风格|                                   |I'm the cool dad. That's- That's my thing.
我酷毙了  我会上网|                                   |I'm hip. I- I surf the Web.
我会发短信  LOL意思是癫狂笑  |                                   |I text. "LOL"- Laugh out loud. 
OMG意思是饿滴神|                                   |"OMG"- Oh, my God.
WTF意思是苦逼脸|                                   |"WTF"- Why the face?
[WTF=What the FUCK意思是搞毛啊]
《歌舞青春》里所有的舞我都会跳|                                   |Um, you know, I know all the dances to High School Musical, so-
*我们现在欢聚一堂*|                                   |*We're all in this together *
*没错*|                                   |*Yes, we are*
*我们都是大明星  嘻唰唰嘻唰唰*|                                   |*We're all stars Something, something you know it*
-妈妈  爸爸  -什么事|                                   |- Mom! Dad! - What happened?
-卢克用枪射我  -我不是故意的|                                   |- Luke just shot me! - I didn't mean to.
-你没事吧  -没事才怪|                                   |- Are you okay? - No.
这小贱人用枪射我|                                   |The little bitch shot me.
-别说脏话  -只是塑料枪  这是意外|                                   |- Language!  They're only plastic BBs. It was an accident.
早就告诉你  给他枪就会出事|                                   |What did I tell you would happen if you got him a gun?
-你看着办吧  -老弟  是你不对哦|                                   |- Deal with this. - Buddy, uncool.
这就完了吗  不行  不行|                                   |That's it? That's- No, no, no, no.
我们说好他用枪射了别人  你就得射他的|                                   |The agreement was that if he shoots someone, you shoot him.
-我们当时是认真的吗  -当然是真的|                                   |- We were serious about that? - Yes, we were.
所以你现在要按说好的执行|                                   |And now you have to follow through.
-我错了  -你就装吧|                                   |- I'm so sorry. - Liar.
-去吧  -他还要去参加生日会呢|                                   |- Go. - He's got a birthday party.
生日会和家法哪个更重要  爸爸|                                   |What's more important here, Dad?
你可以之后再射他  他两点就能到家|                                   |You can shoot him afterwards. He'll be home at 2:00.
两点不行|                                   |I can't shoot him at 2:00.
我两点还得带人去看房子|                                   |I'm showing a house at 2:00.
-三点吧  -不行  三点他有足球赛|                                   |- What about 3:00? - No, he's got a soccer game at 3:00.
然后我们五点就得去赴宴|                                   |And then- Oh, we gotta leave for that dinner thing at 5:00.
4点15吧  你可以在那时候射他|                                   |4:15. You could shoot him at 4:15.
行  那个时候我有空|                                   |Yeah, I guess that works for me. Oh!
-射卢克  -抱歉老弟  铁板钉钉了|                                   |- "Shoot Luke." - Sorry, dude. It's on the calendar.
别这样啊|                                   |Oh, come on!
我不想踢足球了  那是小孩儿玩的|                                   |I'm quitting soccer. It is a game for children.
不  你不能放弃|                                   |No, you're not quitting.
对方之所以会进球|                                   |You would have stopped that goal
完全是因为你光顾着看小姑娘了|                                   |if you weren't staring at that little girl.
她不是小姑娘  她是成熟的女人|                                   |She is not a girl. She's a woman.
歌洛莉亚  你犯得着非要和|                                   |You know, Gloria, that little blowup with that other mom
那个妈妈吵架吗|                                   |Why do you have to do things like that?
如果有人敢对我的家人说三道四|                                   |If somebody says something about my family,
-我一定  -我只是说|                                   |- I'm going to - I'm just saying.
你火气应该小一点  就这样|                                   |You could take it down here a little bit. That's all.
没错  你总是这么忍气吞声的|                                   |Oh, yeah. 'Cause that's where you live, down here.
-可我咽不下这口气  -可是|                                   |- But I live up here! - Yeah, but,
我只是说  你别那么容易激动嘛|                                   |you don't have to be so emotional all the time.That's all I'm saying.
曼尼  你也这么觉得吧|                                   |Manny, you're with me on this, right?
我要告诉布兰达·费德曼我爱她|                                   |I wanna tell Brenda Feldman I love her.
-天啊  -曼尼  她都16岁了|                                   |- Oh, for God sakes. - Manny, she's 16.
你不就找了年长的对象吗|                                   |Oh. It's okay for you to take an older lover?
-嘿  说话注意点  -我要去她上班的商场|                                   |- Hey, watch it. - I wanna go to the mall where she works.
不过我先得换上我的白衬衫  丝绸的那件|                                   |But first I need to get my white shirt, the silk one.
好吧  如果你真想这么做的话|                                   |Okay. If that's what you really want to do.
说真的  不是我要当恶毒的后爹|                                   |Seriously. Not to be the evil stepdad,
可你要真穿着那臃肿的白衬衣|                                   |but if you put on a puffy white shirt...
去向16岁的姑娘告白|                                   |and declare your love for a 16-year-old,
你会被扒得只剩条白内裤|                                   |you're gonna be swinging from the flagpole
然后被吊在旗杆上|                                   |in your puffy white underpants.
-停车  -你去哪儿|                                   |- Stop the car. - Oh, where are you going?
看到没  你伤他的心了|                                   |See? You hurt his feelings.
要是这能让他变得坚强点|                                   |Ah- Well, if it toughens him up a little bit then-
我的妈呀  他居然去采野花了|                                   |Oh, geez. He's picking flowers.
曼尼是个多情种  和他爹一个样|                                   |Manny's very passionate, just like his father.
我的前夫  风度翩翩  但太疯狂了|                                   |My first husband- he's very handsome, but too crazy.
我们不是在吵架就是在做爱|                                   |It seemed like all we did was fight and make love,
吵架  做爱  吵架  做爱|                                   |fight and make love, fight and make love.
说真的  有一次  我们从窗口摔下去了|                                   |One time, I'm not kidding you, we fell out the window together.
你们当时在吵架还是做爱|                                   |Which- Which one were you doing?
我也是第一次听说这事|                                   |I'm hearing this for the first time.
你不担心吗|                                   |This doesn't worry you?
她在飞机上就没怎么睡  现在还很清醒|                                   |She barely slept on the plane and she's still wide awake.
-别想多了  -不想才怪|                                   |- Oh, stop worrying. - I can't.
那个孤儿院里都是女人|                                   |That- That orphanage was all women.
也许离开女性柔软的怀抱  她就睡不着  |                                   |Maybe she just- she can't fall asleep unless she feels a woman's shape.
-有可能  -那你抱着她|                                   |- I guess that's possible. - So here.
你这话是什么意思|                                   |What the hell is that supposed to mean?
没错  |                                   |Yes,
在等待领养孩子的期间  我是长胖了一点|                                   |I've gained a few extra pounds while we were expecting the baby,
过程相当艰辛|                                   |which has been very difficult.
但显然你的身体会|                                   |But apparently your body
产生一些母性的本能反应|                                   |does a nesting, very maternal, primal thing...
来储存养分|                                   |where it retains nutrients-
像是分子生理学那类的|                                   |some sort of molecular physiology thing.
那是科学事实|                                   |But that's science.
人类  根本无力抵抗|                                   |You can't- You can't fight it, so-
-我没别的意思  -你就是话里有话|                                   |- I'm not saying anything. - You're saying everything.
-数到3  -1  2|                                   |- Count to three. - One, two-
-3  -好吧|                                   |- Three. - Okay.
-小卡  真美  -我的天  你喜欢吗|                                   |- Oh, Cam. This is beautiful. - Oh, my God. Do you love it?
当然  我|                                   |Yes, I-
这是什么玩意|                                   |What the hell is that?
我让安珠尔趁我们不在时画的|                                   |I had Andre do it while we were gone.
那是我俩吗  还长着翅膀  |                                   |Is that us, with wings?
我们在她的上方  永远守护着她|                                   |We're floating above her, always there to protect her.
这真让人心安  对吧  莉莉|                                   |Okay. Well, that's reassuring, right, Lily?
我们把你从熟悉的环境中抢出来|                                   |Yes, we tore you away from everything you know,
可别担心  新环境一切"正常"|                                   |but don't worry, things are normal here.
你的大爸二爸可是飞天小精灵哦|                                   |Your fathers are floating fairies.
不行  你能叫安珠尔|                                   |No, can you call Andre,
重新画点不那么基情的东西吗|                                   |have him paint something a little less gay?
另外  我们也该少和安珠尔往来|                                   |By the way, we need to stop having friends
他名字也太娘了|                                   |with names like Andre.
-红发老爹怒火旺盛  -我才不是|                                   |- Redheaded dad is angry daddy. - No, I'm not.
你就是|                                   |Yes, you are.
回来的路上  连胡娇都看出来了|                                   |Even Pepper pointed it out on the way home from the airport.
你看  又一个娘气的名字  胡娇|                                   |Okay, that's another one- Pepper.
你到底怎么不爽|                                   |Okay, what's up?
好吧  听着|                                   |All right, look. I-
我还没有告诉家里领养孩子的事|                                   |I- I never told my family we were adopting a baby.
-而且  -我知道|                                   |- And... - I know.
-你知道  -我不怪你  我了解你家人|                                   |- You do? - Yeah, and I don't blame you. I know your family.
你一告诉他们  他们就开始说三道四|                                   |You'd tell 'em. They'd say something judgmental.
-就是这样  -然后你就会生气|                                   |- Exactly. - You'd get mad.
没错  当爹本该是一件喜事 |                                   |I know. And then something that's supposed to be nothing but joyful
转眼就变成一团混战|                                   |suddenly turns into this huge fight.
谁愿意让事情变得一团糟呢|                                   |And who wants a big, emotional scene like that?
谢谢  谢谢|                                   |Thank you. Thank you.
你能理解我  真是让我松了一口气|                                   |I'm so- I'm so relieved you understand.
所以我邀请了他们今晚来吃饭|                                   |I invited them over for dinner tonight.
-什么  -我也是不得已|                                   |- What? - I had to.
这样下去没完没了  你就只会逃避|                                   |This would have gone on forever. You're an avoider.
不  小卡  我现在就打电话取消这件事|                                   |No. No. No. Cam, I'm calling them right now and canceling.
不准打|                                   |No, you're not.
今晚你得把领养的事告诉全家人|                                   |You're telling your family you adopted a baby, tonight.
你就是喜欢逃避  连朗吉娜都这么说|                                   |And you do have avoidance issues. Even Longinus said so.
你自己听听  这些名字有多娘|                                   |Are- Are you really not hearing these names?
你们别管了  我来开门|                                   |Don't answer it! I'll get it!
你好  你一定是迪兰吧|                                   |Hi. Hey, you must be Dylan.
-是的  迪兰  -我是海莉的妈妈|                                   |- Hey. Dylan. Yeah. - I'm Haley's mother.
-我们走吧  -那个|                                   |- Come on. Let's go. - Okay. Um-
等一下|                                   |Hang on one second.
迪兰  你还在念高中吗|                                   |Dylan, you're still in high school?
-是  我高三了   -高三  很好|                                   |- Yeah, I'm a senior. -A senior. Okay. Cool.
菲尔  亲爱的  这是迪兰  他读高三|                                   |Hey, Phil. Sweetie. Honey. He is Dylan, and he is a senior.
你得给他个下马威|                                   |You have to scare him.
让我瞧瞧这个花心大少|                                   |Let me meet this "Playa."
在下菲尔·邓菲|                                   |Phil Dunphy, yo.
就是这样  你只需死盯着他们看|                                   |It's like that. You just- You just stare down at 'em,
用眼神中的杀气震住他们|                                   |let the eyes do the work.
你嘴上说着  没问题|                                   |Your mouth might be saying, "Hey, we cool,"
可你的眼神说  才怪|                                   |but your eyes are like, "No, we not."
很高兴见到你  才怪|                                   |"Nice to meet you." "No, it's not."
挺不错嘛|                                   |"It's all good."
才怪|                                   |"No, it's not."
-我看你俩已经  -等一下|                                   |- Okay, I see you two guys- - Wait, wait, wait.
你们俩|                                   |You two-
你俩要坦诚相待  懂吗  小子|                                   |You two keep it real, know what I mean, son?
不太懂|                                   |Not really.
-求求你  别说了  -没事|                                   |- Please, stop. - That's cool.
-妈呀我的背  -亲爱的|                                   |- Ow. Oh, God! That's my back. - Oh, honey. Sweetheart.
我被婴儿油滑倒了|                                   |Ow! Oh! I slipped in the baby oil.
你哪儿冒出来的啊|                                   |"Oh, where you from originally?"
单挑的话  我轻而易举就能放倒你|                                   |"I could defeat you if it came to a physical confrontation."
我不知道该怎么办  要打电话叫医生吗|                                   |I don't know about this. Should I call a doctor?
不用不用  好了|                                   |No, no, no, no, no. Okay.
-小样儿挺强壮的啊  -谢谢夸奖|                                   |- You're very strong, homes. - Thanks.
-好  轻轻放下我  -好了|                                   |- Okay. Nice- Nice soft landing. - There you go.
-行了我们走吧  -我还侧躺着|                                   |- Okay, let's go. Come on. - I am on my side though.
现在只需把我放平  就没事了|                                   |So just flip me right back, and we're good.
就没事了|                                   |We'll be good.
只需要把我翻过来就行|                                   |I just need to get flipped right on my back,
就没事了|                                   |and we should be fine. So-
布兰达·费尔曼|                                   |Brenda Feldman.
-你拿的什么  -我为布兰达·费尔曼写的诗|                                   |- What is that? - A poem I have written for Brenda Feldman.
不用想也知道|                                   |Of course it is.
我将心事化为文字  将文字用于行动|                                   |I put my thoughts into words and now my words into action.
你取消行动的话  我就给你50块钱|                                   |Hey, I'll give you 50 bucks not to do this.
我才11岁而已  要那么多钱干什么|                                   |I'm 11 years old. What am I gonna do with money?
你这年纪要16岁的花姑娘又能干什么|                                   |What are you gonna do with a 16-year-old?
-他就像个斗牛士  -你见过斗牛吗|                                   |- He's like a bullfighter. - Mmm. You ever see a bullfight?
我看不下去了  -我知道你心情不好 |                                   |I can't watch this. - You're in such a bad mood.
我也知道原因  因为那人以为你是我爸爸|                                   |And I know why. It's because that man thought you were my father.
-不是的  -就是|                                   |- No. - Yes.
-不是  -你这样否认时  就代表是|                                   |- No. - When you say "No" like that, it's always "Yes."
别这样  我们都到商场了|                                   |Come on. We're in the mall.
给你买点年轻的衣服吧|                                   |Let's get you, like, some younger clothes.
-那边有家店  -我不需要年轻的衣服|                                   |- There's a store there. - I don't need any younger clothes.
我也不在乎那些|                                   |And I don't care what some jackass
穿着破牛仔裤的混蛋如何看我|                                   |in a pair of ripped jeans thinks about me.
没错  你不用在乎他们|                                   |Good. You shouldn't.
你只要在乎我的想法就行了|                                   |You should only care what I think.
我爱你  我不在意你的年纪|                                   |I love you, and I don't care how old you are.
所以别郁闷了  对曼尼也别那么凶|                                   |So stop being a gloomy goose and stop being so hard on Manny.
我对曼尼严格只是因为|                                   |The only reason I'm hard on Manny...
我不想让他出洋相|                                   |Is just because I don't wanna see him make a fool of himself.
我从这儿都能闻到他的发胶味了|                                   |And I can smell that hair goo of his from here.
我不知道他那里会发生什么|                                   |Look, I don't know what's gonna happen to him over there.
可你是他的家人  这就意味着|                                   |But you're his family now, and that means only one thing-
你只可背后送春风  不可当面唾其脸|                                   |You be the wind in his back, not the spit in his face.
-啥玩意  -这是我妈常挂嘴边的话|                                   |- What? -It's something my mom always says.
用西班牙语说很华丽的 |                                   |It's gorgeous in Spanish.
瞧  他来了|                                   |Look, he's there.
-她名花有主了  -真遗憾  小宝贝|                                   |- She has a boyfriend. - Oh, I'm sorry, mi nino.
我把心献给了她|                                   |I gave her my heart,
她却还了一幅把我画成老式警长的图|                                   |she gave me a picture of me as an old-time sheriff.
-我真傻是吧  -才不是呢小宝贝|                                   |- That was pretty stupid of me, wasn't it? - No, mi amor.
你是勇气可嘉  对吧  杰  勇气可嘉|                                   |It was brave. Right, Jay? Brave.
下次你就会进步了|                                   |W-Well, you'll know better next time.
来  我们买椒盐卷去|                                   |Come on. Let's get a pretzel.
没事  我挺喜欢这画的|                                   |Mentira. A me se me gusta.
先生  不好意思|                                   |Uh, excuse me, sir.
在商场散步锻炼的人必须靠右边走|                                   |We ask that all mall-walkers stay to the right.
艾丽克斯  出去  妈妈你看她|                                   |Alex, get out! Mom!
艾丽克斯  别去烦你姐姐|                                   |Alex, leave your sister alone.
我只是进去拿我的书而已  至于吗|                                   |I was just getting my book. Gosh.
我知道  亲爱的  可你要尊重个人隐私|                                   |I know, sweetie. But you need to respect their privacy.
-他们在楼上干嘛呢  -没干嘛|                                   |- What are they doing up there? - Nothing.
躺在她床上并肩看电影|                                   |Lying on her bed, watching a movie.
很好  很好|                                   |Okay. Okay.
我在为今晚的聚餐准备蛋糕|                                   |Um, I'm making a cake for tonight.
你想帮我做糖霜吗|                                   |You wanna help me with the frosting?
好啊|                                   |Sure.
要是海莉怀孕了|                                   |So, you know, if Haley got pregnant,
你会假装她得了腮腺炎  请假在家|                                   |would you ever pretend she has mono for a few months,
然后告诉别人那孩子是你的吗|                                   |and then, like, tell everyone the baby's yours?
-什么  -有个高中生请了4个月病假|                                   |- What? - This senior at school was "Out sick" for four months,
可吉娜·瑞斯尼克发誓说看到她|                                   |but Jenna Resnick swears she saw her breast-feeding
在自助洗车站给孩子喂奶|                                   |at a coin-op car wash.
老弟  你穿了多少衣服啊|                                   |Buddy, what are you wearing?
-没穿多少  -把外套脱了|                                   |- Nothing. - Uh-uh. No jacket.
只能戴一顶帽子|                                   |One hat.
你穿了几条内裤啊|                                   |How many pairs of underwear do you have on?
就1条  |                                   |One.
是6条|                                   |Six.
首先  看海莉怀孕变胖还蛮爽的|                                   |First of all, it would be really cool to see Haley that fat.
更酷的是  |                                   |And how awesome would it be
多了个假弟弟  实际上是我亲外甥|                                   |to have a fake little brother who's really my nephew.
海莉才不会怀孕|                                   |Haley is not getting pregnant.
-我只是说假如  -我知道|                                   |- Just saying "If." - I know.
我知道你喜欢找你姐的茬儿|                                   |And I know you like to make trouble for your sister,
不过这次不管用了|                                   |but it's not gonna work this time.
知道为啥吗  因为你姐是个好女孩|                                   |You know why? 'Cause your sister's a good girl.
我明白  因为她和我当年一模一...|                                   |I know. I was just like her when I was-
要知道  我也不想这么做|                                   |I want you to know, I'm not enjoying this.
可你得吸取这个教训|                                   |But this is an important lesson that you're learning.
所以  记好了  记住了|                                   |So, soak it. Keep it.
你站太近了  这样会很疼的|                                   |You're too close. It's gonna hurt.
就是要你疼|                                   |It's supposed to hurt.
-你干嘛贱贱地笑  -我笑了吗|                                   |- And why are you smiling? - I'm- What?
算了  我下不了手|                                   |Oh, forget it. I can't do this.
就是要让你害怕  你已经学到教训了|                                   |The point is you're scared. I think you've learned your lesson.
妈  你干什么啊|                                   |Mom! What are you doing?
我是来放洗好的衣服|                                   |Oh, hey! I was just, um, dropping off some laundry.
-打扰到你们了吗  -当然|                                   |- Is this a bad time? - Yeah.
那我走好了|                                   |Oh. Okay.
你能把门带上吗|                                   |Uh, can you shut the door, please?
我们还是让门开着吧|                                   |Actually, we're just gonna go ahead and leave that open.
为啥|                                   |Why?
因为这种场景我见多了|                                   |Because I have, uh, seen this little show before-
和高大的学长共卧一塌|                                   |Lying on the bed with a tall senior.
上一秒还只是一起看《鹰冠庄园》的朋友|                                   |One minute you're just friends, watching Falcon Crest,
下一秒你们就钻进游戏桌下|                                   |and the next you're lying underneath the air hockey table
宽衣解带了|                                   |with your bra in your pocket.
妈妈|                                   |Mom!
-你打到我的骨头了  -纯属意外|                                   |- You hit my bone! - It was an accident!
-我以为你是我哥们呢  -我是啊|                                   |- I thought you were my friend! - I am your friend.
爸爸  你必须和妈妈谈谈|                                   |Dad! Dad, Dad. You have got to talk to Mom.
她简直是疯了  而且丢尽了我的脸|                                   |She is, like, completely freaking out and embarrassing me!
宝贝  你妈是不像你爸那么通情达理|                                   |Honey, your mom isn't always as cool about things as-
这玩意怎么回事啊|                                   |What is with this thing?
我爸|                                   |My dad.
我爸对这事还是不太习惯|                                   |Uh, my dad still isn't completely comfortable with this.
已经过了5年了  他还是无法完全接受|                                   |Um- He-He still does this thing. It's been five years now.
每次他要进入我和小卡在的房间时|                                   |And he still does this thing where he announces himself...
他都会先喊一声|                                   |before walking into any room we're in...
以防撞见我和小卡亲嘴|                                   |just to make sure he doesn't have to ever see us kiss.
要是我妈也有这个习惯就好了|                                   |Wish my mother had that system.
-还记得吗  -以后再说|                                   |- Remember? - Not now.
我真不敢相信你这么对我|                                   |I still can't believe you did this to me.
你能高兴点吗  这是个庆祝会啊|                                   |Would you get in the spirit of things? It's a celebration.
天啊|                                   |Oh, God.
-我去给莉莉打扮一下  -好|                                   |- Okay, I'm gonna go get Lily ready. - Okay.
-我要你对他们实话实说  -好吧|                                   |- And I want you to just come straight out with it. - All right.
听话  你能做到的|                                   |Okay. You can do this.
来个运动员式的撞胸|                                   |Yeah. Sports guy chest bump.
-不要  -来撞一个|                                   |- No. - Sports guy chest bump.
-小卡  好了  -上吧|                                   |- Cam. Oh! All right. Go - Do it.
抱歉|                                   |Sorry.
-你好啊  -大家好啊|                                   |- How are you? - Hi, guys. Hey.
看起来很美味啊  谢谢|                                   |That looks good. Oh, thank you. Thanks.
不用谢  打开吧  爸爸后脚马上就到|                                   |Don't thank us. Open it. Dad is coming right behind.
有人吗  我们要进来了|                                   |Knock, knock! We're here. Coming in!
别担心爸爸  我们没在里面搞基|                                   |Don't worry, Dad. Nothing gay going on here.
能帮你脱下这缤纷外套和闪亮小帽吗|                                   |May I take your multicolored coat and bejeweled cap?
-拿去吧  -杰你好啊|                                   |- Yeah. Yeah. - Hey, Jay.
-你好  歌洛莉亚  -你好|                                   |- Gloria, hi. - Hi.
-老爸你还好吗  -歌洛莉亚  你好|                                   |- How are you? Hi, Dad. - Hi, Gloria. How are you?
-裙子真漂亮  -谢谢你  菲尔[摸摸]|                                   |- Oh, what a beautiful dress. - Ay, thank you, Phil.
好吧  |                                   |Okay. 
菲尔|                                   |Oh, hey, Phil.
["Phil菲尔"和"feel触摸"音相似]
她是叫你名字  不是要你去摸|                                   |That's how she says "Phil." Not "Feel." Phil.
-旅行怎么样  -挺好的  真的  |                                   |- So how was your trip? - It was good. It was good actually.
关于这事|                                   |But, um, about that, I- I
我有些事要告诉你们|                                   |have something that I need to tell you guys.
我们去越南不光是为了旅游|                                   |Um- Uh, we didn't just go to Vietnam for pleasure.
我们有重要消息宣布|                                   |We, uh, kind of have some big news.
天啊  要是小卡隆了胸  我立马走人|                                   |Oh, God. If Cam comes out here with boobs, I'm leaving.
-爸爸  -我希望你的家长没让你觉得丢人  妈|                                   |- Dad. - I hope he didn't embarrass you, Mom.
别管她  海莉今天首次带男生回家|                                   |Oh, don't mind her. Haley had her first boy over today...
菲尔就给了他一枪|                                   |And Phil shot him.
总之  一年前|                                   |Anyway, um, so, about- about a year ago,
小卡和我开始渴望有一个|                                   |Cam and I started feeling this longing, you know,
有一个  孩子|                                   |for something more, like, uh, maybe a baby?
-这主意很糟糕  -你说糟糕是什么意思|                                   |- Ooh, that's a bad idea. - What do you mean, "Bad idea"?
孩子需要有妈妈|                                   |Well, kids need a mother.
如果你们俩无聊了  可以养条狗|                                   |I mean if you two guys are bored, get a dog.
我们不是闲得无聊  爸|                                   |Okay, we're not bored, Dad.
我支持米奇尔  尽管你不是我亲生的|                                   |I support you, Mitchell, even though you're not my son.
我觉得爸爸的意思是|                                   |I-I-I-I think what Dad is trying to say...
米奇尔  你有点紧张兮兮的|                                   |is that, Mitchell, you're a little uptight.
孩子就意味着麻烦  你没法处理这种事|                                   |Kids bring chaos, and- and you don't handle it well.
爸爸可不是这个意思|                                   |That's not what Dad's saying.
这是你的意思|                                   |That's what you're saying.
而且是从另一个角度羞辱了我|                                   |And it's insulting in a whole different way.
好了  各位都冷静点|                                   |Okay, people. Let's all "Chillax."
-卡梅隆舅夫呢  -多谢多谢|                                   |- Hey, where's Uncle Cameron? - Thank you. Thank you.
总算有人发现他不在了  而不是光羞辱我|                                   |Someone who's not insulting me notices he's not here.
原来你的重要消息就是这个啊|                                   |Oh, so that's the big announcement, huh?
你俩分手了吗|                                   |You two broke up.
领养个孩子也挽救不了破裂的婚姻|                                   |Well- Well, a baby wasn't gonna help that anyway.
老实说  你们分了也好|                                   |And let me tell you. You're better off,
他就喜欢小题大做|                                   |because he was a bit of a drama queen.
不是的  打住  打住|                                   |No, no, no. Stop. Stop. No.
你们到我家来  还羞辱我和我的男朋友|                                   |You come into my house and you insult me and my boyfriend,
而且他才没有小题大做|                                   |who, by the way, is not that dramatic-
我们领养了一个宝宝|                                   |We adopted a baby.
她名叫莉莉|                                   |Her name is Lily.
-激动吧  -停下来|                                   |- Exciting! - Just turn it off.
我停不下来  这就是我的个性|                                   |I can't turn it off. It's who I am.
-我是说音乐  -关音乐啊|                                   |- The music. - Oh, yes, the music.
来和莉莉打招呼吧|                                   |Come say hi to Lily.
看看这个小公主|                                   |Ay, miren a la princesita.
真是个小公主|                                   |The little princess.
-她好可爱  -多谢夸奖|                                   |- She's so cute! - Thank you.
让我看看  让我看看|                                   |Let me see her. Let me see her.
你好啊  莉莉|                                   |Hi there, Lily.
莉莉  对她来说不是很难发音吗|                                   |"Lily." Isn't that gonna be hard for her to say?
-菲尔打住  -我说|                                   |- Phil. - Excuse me.
我知道我说了领养这个主意很糟糕|                                   |Okay, I-I-I know that I said I thought this was a bad idea.
可我又懂什么呢|                                   |But, uh, what do I know?
我也不是个模范父亲|                                   |I mean, it's not like I wrote the book on fatherhood.
一辈子都想做好爸爸  可我还是搞砸了|                                   |Been trying all my life to get it right. I'm still screwing up.
-对吧曼尼  -我在车上为此写了首歌|                                   |- Right, Manny? - I wrote a song about it in the car.
意料之中|                                   |Of course you did.
不管怎样  我为你们感到高兴|                                   |Anyway, I'm happy for you.
你们要知道|                                   |And, uh, you should know that, uh,
我不是来唾你们脸的|                                   |I'm not here to spit in your face,
我是来给你们  吹吹后背春风的|                                   |I'm here to... blow at your back.
-我不懂你的意思  -我也不懂|                                   |- I don't understand what that means. - I don't-
这话用西班牙语说比较好听|                                   |Well, it's- it's supposed to sound better in Spanish.
[良言一句三冬暖  恶语伤人六月寒]
真好听  真美|                                   |Oh, that's beautiful. That's really nice.
也谢谢你|                                   |And thank you too.
总之  米奇|                                   |Anyhow, Mitch, uh-
不用了  爸爸|                                   |No, Dad, it's- it's- -
-我来抱她  -她哭了|                                   |- I got her. I got her. - Oh, she's crying.
她要爷爷抱  她要爸爸抱|                                   |She wants her grandpa! She wants her daddy!
-想见见爷爷吗  -开什么玩笑|                                   |- Do you wanna meet Grandpa? - What? Are you kidding?
她是自家人了  让我瞧瞧你这跟屁虫|                                   |She's one of us now. Let me see the little pot sticker.
你真是个小可爱  对吗|                                   |Hey, you're a cutie, aren't you?
看看这个|                                   |Ah. Look at this.
我们来自不同的世界  但我们彼此相容|                                   |We're from different worlds, yet we somehow fit together.
爱将我们紧紧相连  共度风风雨雨|                                   |Love is what binds us, through fair or stormy weather.
我到你的前面  只有一事相许|                                   |I stand before you now with only one agenda-
我的心只属于你|                                   |"To let you know my heart is yours,
布兰达·费尔曼|                                   |Feldman comma Brenda."
不是吧我靠|                                   |I mean, seriously.
至今为止  卢克在篮球上还没赢过我|                                   |Luke, so far, hasn't beaten me in basketball.
2比0  2比0  来吧|                                   |It's 2-0. 2-0. Okay. Okay.
-手下败将  滚吧  -爸爸  住手|                                   |- Get that weak stuff out of my kitchen! - Dad, stop it!
帮个忙好吗  站过去|                                   |Can you do me a favor? Just grab-
篮下的滋味如何|                                   |How's the weather down there?
等到他赢过我的那一天|                                   |But when the day comes that he does win-
如果有那么一天|                                   |if- you know- if/when-
他打败了我  我会说|                                   |he beats me, I'm just gonna be like,
干得好  干得好|                                   |"Well done. Well done."
就这样支持他|                                   |Just, like, let him- Just support him...
就是这样|                                   |in- in- in that kind of stuff.
我可能会说|                                   |I mean, I'd probably want to go, like,
三局两胜才算赢  再来一局什么的|                                   |two out of three and just see what happens there, but-
